There is a very strong tradition and saying of the companions of the prophet (peace and blessings of allaah be upon him) in this regard.
Abdullah ibn umar (may allah be pleased with him) تعالیٰ they say.
مَن بَنَ بِبِلَادِ الْعَاجِم.
Those who lived in the areas of non-muslims, non-muslim nations, in their cities, in their countries.
وَصَنَعَ نَيْرُوزَهُمْ وَمِحْرَجَانَهُمْ.
Let their neeruz and mehrejan celebrate their eids themselves.
وَتَشَبَّحَ بِهِمْ حَتَّى يَمُوتُ وَهُوَ كَذَلِكَ.
And he may imitate them and in that state he may die.
خُشِرَ مَاہُمْ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةِ.
He will be resurrected with them on the day of judgment.
I am reading the hadith again.
They say مَن بَنَ بِبِلَادِ الْعَاجِم.
Those who go and settle in the land of foreigners.
وَسَنَعْ نیروزَهُمْ وَمِحْرَجَانَهُمْ.
And their nerves and embarrassments.
That is, celebrate their eids and celebrate them yourself.
وَتَشَبَّحَ بِهِمْ حَتَّى يَمُوتُ وَهُوَ كَذَلِكَ.
And imitate them.
Even if it means death.
خُشِرَ مَاہُمْ يَوْمَ الْقِيَامَةِ.
His fate will be with them on the day of judgment.
It turned out that whoever imitates whom in the world.
His end will be with him in the hereafter.
As we saw in the hadith.
مَن تَشَبَّحَ بِقَوْمٍ فَهُوَ مِنْهُمْ.
Whoever imitates the nation they are from among them.
This tradition has been narrated by imam al-bayhaqi in the book al-jaziya.
Hadith number 18863.
18863.
So, from this hadith, this is the statement of the companions.
But what are you talking about?
This is not a man saying this from his own opinion.
That is why this saying.
That is, the ruling will be accepted.
Rather, it would have been further confirmed by this hadith.
Which is the original hadith of this chapter.
مَن تَشَبَّحَ بِقَوْمٍ فَهُوَ مِنْهُمْ.
Whoever imitates the nation they are from among them.
So it follows that.
Celebrating other nations' holidays.
It is not permissible in islam.
Our eids are for allah. تعالیٰ did.
Set for us.
No one has the authority to celebrate eid.
Eid is a sacred command.
Which is from allah.
It is based on revelation.
A man on his own behalf.
Can't make it.
It is important to remember this.