Similarly, one of the etiquettes of the worldly mosque is not to talk about worldly and vulgar things in the mosque.
The prophet of allah (peace and blessings of allah be upon him) says:
سَيَكُونُ فِي آخِرِ زَمَانِ قَوْمٌ.
There will be some people like that in the end times.
يَجْلِسُونَ فِي الْمَسَاجِدِ حِلَقًا حِلَقًا.
They will sit in circles in the mosques.
اِمَامُهُمُ الدُّنْيَا.
اُن the goal will be the world.
They will sit in the mosque but…
The gossip will be from the whole world.
The goal will be the world. اُس from sitting.
No afterlife, no reward.
فَلَا تُجَالِسُوہُم.
So don't sit with them.
فَإِنَّهُ لَيْسَ لِلَّهِ فِيهِمْ حَاجَةً.
Because allah will have no need of them.
That is, they will have no place to sit in the presence of allah.
Imam al-tabarani narrated this.
And this is a tradition of beauty.
This shows that.
Gossiping about the world in the mosque.
And make that the goal.
And to do it sitting in the mosque.
And talking nonsense in mosques.
There is no room for such things.
Let's talk a little bit here and there.
Okay, but turn mosques into dens of gossip.
God forbid, this is not a good thing.
And especially in this one.
Things are like that in the world too.
There are trade issues.
And there are things that are against the atmosphere of the mosque.
So this is not right.